<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bano on David Pilato</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/series/bano/</link><description>Recent content in bano on David Pilato</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022, David Pilato, France</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://david.pilato.fr/series/bano/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enriching your postal addresses with Elastic stack - part 3</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-03-24-enriching-your-postal-addresses-with-elastic-stack-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-03-24-enriching-your-postal-addresses-with-elastic-stack-part-3/</guid><description>This blog post is part of a series of 3:
Importing Bano dataset with Logstash Using Logstash to lookup for addresses in Bano index Using Logstash to enrich an existing dataset with Bano In the previous post, we described how we can transform a postal address to a normalized one with also the geo location point or transform a geo location point to a postal address.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have an existing dataset we want to enrich.</description></item><item><title>Enriching your postal addresses with Elastic stack - part 2</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-03-23-enriching-your-postal-addresses-with-elastic-stack-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 10:20:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-03-23-enriching-your-postal-addresses-with-elastic-stack-part-2/</guid><description>This blog post is part of a series of 3:
Importing Bano dataset with Logstash Using Logstash to lookup for addresses in Bano index Using Logstash to enrich an existing dataset with Bano In the previous post, we described how we indexed data coming from the BANO project so we now have indices containing all the french postal addresses.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can do now with this dataset.
Searching for addresses Good. Can we use a search engine to search?</description></item><item><title>Enriching your postal addresses with Elastic stack - part 1</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-03-22-enriching-your-postal-addresses-with-elastic-stack-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:31:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-03-22-enriching-your-postal-addresses-with-elastic-stack-part-1/</guid><description>This blog post is part of a series of 3:
Importing Bano dataset with Logstash Using Logstash to lookup for addresses in Bano index Using Logstash to enrich an existing dataset with Bano I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why, but I love the postal address use case. Often in my career I had to deal with that information. Very often the information is not well formatted so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find the information you need when you have as an input a not so nice dataset.</description></item></channel></rss>