<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kibana on David Pilato</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/tags/kibana/</link><description>Recent content in kibana on David Pilato</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022, David Pilato, France</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 17:35:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://david.pilato.fr/tags/kibana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>And the beats go on!</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2016-03-17-and-the-beats-go-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 17:35:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2016-03-17-and-the-beats-go-on/</guid><description>Sounds like a cool music, right? At least this is one of my favorite tracks.
May be some of you already know that, I enjoy doing some DeeJaying for my friends.
But today, I want to speak about another kind of beats. Elastic beats!
Elastic Beats
Actually my favorite funky music track is a one from Georges Duke: Reach out! But this is another story&amp;hellip;
Beats So what are beats?
Beats are lightweight shippers that collect and ship all kinds of operational data to Elasticsearch</description></item><item><title>Understanding Zipf's law</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2016-01-05-understanding-zipfs-law/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 12:13:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2016-01-05-understanding-zipfs-law/</guid><description>I just discovered a nice video which explains the Zipf&amp;rsquo;s law.
I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if I can index the french lexique from Université de Savoie and find some funny things based on that&amp;hellip;
Download french words wget http://www.lexique.org/listes/liste_mots.txt head -20 liste_mots.txt What do we have?
It&amp;rsquo;s a CSV file (tabulation as separator):
1_graph 8_frantfreqparm 0 279.84 1 612.10 2 1043.90 3 839.32 4 832.23 5 913.87 6 603.42 7 600.61 8 908.03 9 1427.45 a 4294.90 aa 0.</description></item><item><title>Building a directory map with ELK</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-12-10-building-a-directory-map-with-elk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 09:28:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-12-10-building-a-directory-map-with-elk/</guid><description>I gave a BBL talk recently and while chatting with attendees, one of them told me a simple use case he covered with elasticsearch: indexing metadata files on a NAS with a simple ls -lR like command. His need is to be able to search on a NAS for files when a user wants to restore a deleted file.
As you can imagine a search engine is super helpful when you have hundreds of millions files!</description></item><item><title>Index Twitter on found</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-11-17-index-twitter-on-found/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 11:51:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-11-17-index-twitter-on-found/</guid><description>Some months ago, I published a recipe on how to index Twitter with Logstash and Elasticsearch.
I have the same need today as I want to monitor Twitter when we run the elastic FR meetup (join us by the way if you are in France!).
Well, this recipe can be really simplified and actually I don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste my time anymore on building and managing elasticsearch and Kibana clusters anymore.
Let&amp;rsquo;s use a Found by elastic cluster instead.</description></item><item><title>Indexing Twitter with Logstash and Elasticsearch</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-06-01-indexing-twitter-with-logstash-and-elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 16:23:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-06-01-indexing-twitter-with-logstash-and-elasticsearch/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m often running some demos during conferences where we have a booth. As many others, I&amp;rsquo;m using Twitter feed as my datasource.
I have been using Twitter river plugin for many years but, you know, rivers have been deprecated.
Logstash 1.5.0 provides a safer and more flexible way to deal with tweets with its twitter input.
Let&amp;rsquo;s do it!
Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you have already elasticsearch 1.5.2, Logstash 1.5.0 and Kibana 4.0.2 running on your laptop or on a cloud instance.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx France 2015</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-05-02-devoxx-france-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 01:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-05-02-devoxx-france-2015/</guid><description>I gave recently a talk at Devoxx France 2015 with Colin Surprenant and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share here some of the examples we used for the talk.
The talk was about &amp;ldquo;what my data look like?&amp;rdquo;.
We said that our manager was asking us to answer some questions:
who are our customers? how do they use our services? what do they think about us on Twitter? Our CRM database So we have a PostgreSQL database containing our data.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Capitaine Train dataset</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-04-28-exploring-capitaine-train-dataset/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 13:31:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-04-28-exploring-capitaine-train-dataset/</guid><description>Recently I saw a tweet where Capitaine Train team started to open data they have collected and enriched or corrected.
Ouvrez, ouvrez, les données structurées. Capitaine Train libère les gares : https://t.co/y6DjWsbALF #opendata
&amp;mdash; Trainline France (@trainline_fr) April 23, 2015 I decided to play a bit with ELK stack and create a simple recipe which can be used with any other CSV like data.
Prerequisites You will need:
Logstash: I&amp;rsquo;m using 1.5.0-rc3. Elasticsearch: I&amp;rsquo;m using 1.</description></item></channel></rss>