<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travels on David Pilato</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/tags/travels/</link><description>Recent content in travels on David Pilato</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022, David Pilato, France</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://david.pilato.fr/tags/travels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>7 years! Finding the right balance</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2020-01-10-7-years-finding-the-right-balance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2020-01-10-7-years-finding-the-right-balance/</guid><description>What a ride! 10 employees to around 2000 now. As I imagined 8 years ago, I still think that Elasticsearch (the product) and elastic (the company) are successful.
Becoming a public company did not change a lot my daily activities.
I&amp;rsquo;m still on the road meeting/building the community, specifically in France and making sure people are sharing the same love that we have internally for the products we are building.
I&amp;rsquo;d like this year to focus this anniversary blog post on some items:</description></item><item><title>5 years. What a milestone!</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-01-10-5-years-what-a-milestone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2018-01-10-5-years-what-a-milestone/</guid><description>What a milestone! Can you imagine how changed the company in the last 5 years? From 10 employees when I joined to more than 700 now!
If you want to read again my story, it&amp;rsquo;s there:
2013: Once upon a time&amp;hellip; 2014: Once upon a time: a year later&amp;hellip; 2015: Once upon a time: Make your dreams come true 2016: 3 years! Time flies! 2017: 4 years at elastic! Before speaking about what happened the last 5 years for me, let&amp;rsquo;s modify a bit the script I wrote last year.</description></item><item><title>4 years at elastic!</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2017-01-10-4-years-at-elastic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 18:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2017-01-10-4-years-at-elastic/</guid><description>This post is starting to become a long series 😊
Yeah! That&amp;rsquo;s amazing! I just spent 4 years working at elastic and I&amp;rsquo;m starting my happy 5th year!
If you want to read again my story, it&amp;rsquo;s there:
2013: Once upon a time&amp;hellip; 2014: Once upon a time: a year later&amp;hellip; 2015: Once upon a time: Make your dreams come true 2016: 3 years! Time flies! This year, I will celebrate this by writing a new tutorial&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>3 years! Time flies!</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2016-01-12-3-years-time-flies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 08:37:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2016-01-12-3-years-time-flies/</guid><description>3 years! Can you imagine that? Already 3 years spent working at elastic? Time flies!
2015 has been an uncommon year for me.
Not because Marty Mc Fly and Doc Emmett Brown finally arrived&amp;hellip;
Not because, Han Solo, Leia and friends were finally back again&amp;hellip;
But for technical and also personal reasons.
On a personal side, I had to deal with two major issues which cause some slow down in my professional activities.</description></item><item><title>Once upon a time: Make your dreams come true</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-01-19-once-upon-a-time-make-your-dreams-come-true/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 20:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2015-01-19-once-upon-a-time-make-your-dreams-come-true/</guid><description>Oh wait! Already 2 years spent working for Elasticsearch? Time flies!
After the first year, I wrote that I did 58 talks in 4 countries, 37 towns for about 18 000 kilometers traveled. I was pretty sure that things would continue to grow.
This year, I spoke 78 times! Around 2 talks per week! I did around 48 000 kilometers. 8 000 km more than the earth&amp;rsquo;s circumference! I still can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;hellip; 12 countries. And no need to say that I love giving talks and sharing my enthusiasm about Elasticsearch!</description></item><item><title>Once upon a time: a year later...</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2014-01-10-once-upon-a-time-a-year-later-dot-dot-dot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 09:30:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2014-01-10-once-upon-a-time-a-year-later-dot-dot-dot/</guid><description>I joined Elasticsearch Inc one year ago. Those were pretty exciting days!
But now&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s more than that! Really! You could think that after one year, my motivation would start to decrease. I have the total opposite feeling. Still excited by my job, by the company and by the project, but most of all by the amazing team I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to work with! Everyone is different and each of us adds different value to Elasticsearch. Personally, I learn a lot from my co-workers.</description></item><item><title>Once upon a time...</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2013-01-15-once-upon-a-time-dot-dot-dot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2013-01-15-once-upon-a-time-dot-dot-dot/</guid><description>Once upon a time&amp;hellip;
In fact 2 years ago, I was looking for a way to make Hibernate search distributed on multiple nodes. My first idea was to store indexes in a single database shared by my nodes. Yes, it’s a stupid idea in term of performances but I would like to try to build it.
Digging for source code, I came to the JdbcDirectory class from the compass project. And I saw on the compass front page something talking about the future of Compass and Elasticsearch.</description></item><item><title>Il était une fois : un conte de fées élastique !</title><link>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2013-01-15-il-etait-une-fois-un-conte-de-fees-elastique/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 19:00:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://david.pilato.fr/blog/2013-01-15-il-etait-une-fois-un-conte-de-fees-elastique/</guid><description>Il était une fois&amp;hellip;
En fait, il y a 2 ans, je cherchais un moyen pour distribuer Hibernate search sur plusieurs noeuds. Ma première idée était de stocker les index dans une base de données partagée par les différents noeuds. Oui ! Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;une idée stupide en terme de performances, mais j&amp;rsquo;avais envie d&amp;rsquo;essayer et de construire ce modèle.
Après avoir cherché du code source, je suis finalement tombé sur la classe JdbcDirectory du projet Compass.</description></item></channel></rss>